<resources>
    <string name="app_name">40K Army Builder (New)</string>

    <string name="back_button">Back</string>

    <string name="home_screen_top_bar_text">40K ARMY BUILDER</string>
    <string name="home_screen_button">Enter</string>
    <string name="home_screen_text">Welcome to the Warhammer 40K Army Builder app!</string>

    <string name="faction_overview_list_top_bar_text">FACTIONS</string>

    <string name="faction_overview_details_top_bar_text">FACTION OVERVIEW</string>

    <string name="adepta_sororitas_name">Adepta Sororitas</string>
    <string name="adepta_sororitas_desc">The Adepta Sororitas, colloquially called the \"Sisterhood\", whose military arm is also known as the Sisters of Battle and formerly as the Daughters of the Emperor, are an all-female division of the Imperium of Man\'s state church known as the Ecclesiarchy or, more formally, as the Adeptus Ministorum.\n\nThe Sisterhood\'s Orders Militant serve as the Ecclesiarchy\'s armed forces, mercilessly rooting out spiritual corruption and heresy within Humanity and every organisation of the Adeptus Terra.\n\nThe Sisterhood serves as the Ministorum\'s only official military force because the Decree Passive laid down by the reformist Ecclesiarch Sebastian Thor held that in the wake of the Age of Apostasy\'s Reign of Blood in the 36th Millennium, the Ecclesiarchy cannot maintain any \"men under arms.\"\n\nThis command was supposed to limit the power of the Ecclesiarchy by preventing it from maintaining the massive armies of the faithful Frateris Templar it once used to abuse its power from the 32nd to the 36th Millennia.\n\nHowever, the Adeptus Ministorum has been able to circumvent this decree with the subtle acquiescence of the Inquisition by deploying the all-female military force of the Sisterhood\'s Orders Militant.</string>
    <string name="adepta_sororitas_quote">By bolter shell, flamer burst and melta blast, the mutant, the heretic and the traitor alike are cleansed of their sin of existence. So has it been for five millennia, so shall it be unto the end of time.</string>
    <string name="adepta_sororitas_quote_source">Sister Immaculata</string>

    <string name="adeptus_custodes_name">Adeptus Custodes</string>
    <string name="adeptus_custodes_desc">The Adeptus Custodes, known as the Legio Custodes during the era of the Great Crusade and Horus Heresy, and colloquially as the \"Ten Thousand,\" is the Imperial adepta responsible for protecting the Imperial Palace and the physical body of the Emperor of Mankind, as well as serving as His most important emissaries, His companions, and the keepers of His many secrets. The Custodes is an elite cadre of genetically-engineered transhuman warriors who are even more potent in combat than the Adeptus Astartes. They are to the Space Marines as the Emperor is to His primarchs, and it is rumoured that each was created by the Master of Mankind personally. His might permeates them, burns in their eyes and flows through their veins as surely as their blood. As such, the Adeptus Custodes are widely regarded as the deadliest warriors in the galaxy, Human or otherwise.\n\nWhere Space Marines represent the mass-produced, genetically-engineered soldiers of the Imperium of Man, the Adeptus Custodes are a force of individual warriors, each a bastion in his own right and a sentinel of unmatched capability and singular purpose created to counter any possible threat -- Human, alien or Daemonic. These warriors have stood in the presence of the immortal Emperor of Mankind since before the time of the Unification Wars. For ten thousand Terran years and more, the Custodians have stood watch over their lord and master, serving as the Emperor\'s personal heralds and praetorian bodyguard.</string>
    <string name="adeptus_custodes_quote">For one hundred years I stood my watch amidst the sombre shadows of the Sanctum Imperialis. I was still as a statue, but always ready, always attuned to dangers unseen. Days, months, years passed by in a frenzied blur beyond those walls, yet within, little moved and nothing changed. For one hundred years I did naught but wait, yet had any threat appeared, I would have struck it down in a heartbeat. For one hundred years I stood my watch, and as it ends I can tell you this – patience is a weapon.</string>
    <string name="adeptus_custodes_quote_source">Tybaris Constor, Custodian Warden</string>

    <string name="adeptus_mechanicus_name">Adeptus Mechanicus</string>
    <string name="adeptus_mechanicus_desc">The Adeptus Mechanicus is the official Imperial name within the Adeptus Terra for the Cult Mechanicus or Cult of the Machine based on Mars which provides the Imperium with its scientists, engineers and technicians.\n\nThe tech-adepts of the Mechanicus are the primary keepers of what is viewed as sacred wisdom, a privileged caste of Tech-priests who jealously guard the knowledge required to maintain and construct much of the Imperium\'s advanced technology.\n\nInstead of the Imperial Creed, the servants of the Mechanicus follow their own dark and mysterious scriptures and worship the strange deity they call the Machine God or the \"Omnissiah.\"\n\nAs part of this faith, the Adeptus Mechanicus believes knowledge is the true manifestation of divinity in the universe, and all creatures and artefacts that embody knowledge are holy because of it. The Emperor is the supreme object of worship for the servants of the Mechanicus, for He is the living avatar of the Machine God that is the Omnissiah.\n\nThe Tech-priests of the Adeptus Mechanicus also regard organic flesh as weak and view the removal and replacement of biological tissue with mechanical, bionic parts as sacred. Most elder Tech-priests have few organic parts left and eventually become more machine than man.</string>
    <string name="adeptus_mechanicus_quote">There is no truth in flesh, only betrayal.\nThere is no strength in flesh, only weakness.\nThere is no constancy in flesh, only decay.\nThere is no certainty in flesh but death.</string>
    <string name="adeptus_mechanicus_quote_source">Credo Omnissiah</string>

    <string name="aeldari_name">Aeldari</string>
    <string name="aeldari_desc">The Aeldari, or the Eldar as they were long known to outsiders, are an ancient and highly advanced species of humanoid xenos whose vast empire once extended the width and breadth of the known galaxy.\n\nIn its time, the Aeldari Empire was without equal in the galaxy, spreading across both realspace and the Webway. They counted themselves masters of the stars and every Aeldari was born a potent psyker, their abilities often used to both create and power their almost magical technology.\n\nEven death was no barrier, for when the Aeldari\'s spirits eventually left their mortal bodies they dissolved peacefully back into the Immaterium to be reborn again in new forms, for the Warp did not thirst for Aeldari souls then as it does today.\n\nBut ten millennia ago, the Aeldari\'s overweening pride and their fall into amoral and hedonistic practices led to a cataclysm that all but eradicated their kind and resulted in the birth of the Chaos God Slaanesh, known as \"She Who Thirsts\" to the Aeldari.\n\nDespite their boundless power, the heart of their civilisation was torn out by this catastrophe of their own making, forcing many of the surviving Aeldari to pursue different strategies for survival to protect their souls from being consumed by She Who Thirsts. These strategies have shaped the nature of the surviving Aeldari cultures.</string>
    <string name="aeldari_quote">Trust not in their appearance, for the Eldar are as alien to good, honest men as the vile Tyranids and savage Orks. There is no understanding them for there is nothing to understand - they are a random force in the universe.</string>
    <string name="aeldari_quote_source">Imperial Commander Abriel Hume</string>

    <string name="astra_militarum_name">Astra Militarum</string>
    <string name="astra_militarum_desc">The Astra Militarum, also known as the Imperial Guard in colloquial Low Gothic, is the largest coherent fighting force in the galaxy and serves as the Imperium of Man\'s primary military force and first line of defence from the myriad threats which endanger the existence of the Human race in the 41st Millennium.\n\nIt is comprised of countless billions of men and women -- hundreds of thousands of different regiments, supported by a vast array of light and heavy armoured vehicles that provide the Imperial Guard\'s primary offensive punch. The Astra Militarum is usually the first Imperial force to respond to a threat if a world\'s Planetary Defence Force (PDF) fails to suppress it.\n\nThe primary combat tactic of the Astra Militarum is to overwhelm the enemy with their endless numbers, while at the same time hammer them into submission with devastating artillery and crush them with powerful main battle tanks. As a result, the Astra Militarum is often referred to as the \"Hammer of the Emperor\" -- the sheer amount of force that the Imperial Guard can bring to bear on the enemy is devastating, but is not as direct or as precise as their Space Marine allies in the Adeptus Astartes, who are described as the \"Scalpel of the Emperor\" and specialise in planetary assaults, special operations and decapitation strikes.</string>
    <string name="astra_militarum_quote">No remorse, no mercy, no forgiveness. Not a single step back, not a single moment of hesitation. You will not succumb to fear or doubt, and you will relent only after you have given your last moment for the Emperor. Nothing less than this will be tolerated.</string>
    <string name="astra_militarum_quote_source">Colonel Kostan Drescher, Mordian 18th Iron Guard</string>

    <string name="black_templars_name">Black Templars</string>
    <string name="black_templars_desc">The Black Templars are a Loyalist Second Founding Space Marine Chapter derived from the Imperial Fists\' gene-seed and their primarch, Rogal Dorn. Their origin can be traced back to the Imperial Fists\' defence of Terra during the Horus Heresy.\n\nSince that time, the Black Templars have been on the longest Imperial Crusade the Imperium of Man has ever known to prove their loyalty to the Emperor of Mankind. They are not a Codex Astartes-compliant Chapter and maintain a very different Chapter structure and culture than is the norm amongst most of the Adeptus Astartes.\n\nThey are also deeply unusual amongst the forces of the Adeptus Astartes for venerating the Master of Mankind as a literal god, just like the mortal adherents of the Imperial Cult.\n\nTo prove his loyalty to the Emperor in the wake of the Imperial Fists\' opposition to the Second Founding, the first Chapter Master of the Black Templars -- the High Marshal Sigismund -- assembled a massive war ﬂeet and began the greatest Space Marine Crusade in the history of the Imperium. It has lasted for 10,000 standard years.</string>
    <string name="black_templars_quote">To the darkness I bring fire. To the ignorant I bring faith. Those who welcome these gifts may live, but I will visit naught but death on those who refuse them.</string>
    <string name="black_templars_quote_source">Chaplain Merek Grimaldus</string>

    <string name="blood_angels_name">Blood Angels</string>
    <string name="blood_angels_desc">The Blood Angels are one of the 20 First Founding Legions of the Space Marines and were originally the IXth Legion before the Second Founding broke the Legiones Astartes up into separate Chapters of 1,000 Space Marines each.\n\nThey are well-known across the galaxy for their bloodthirsty nature in battle, and feared for the curse of flawed gene-seed they carry. The Blood Angels are amongst the longest-living of the Adeptus Astartes, with some of the Chapter\'s Space Marines having served the Emperor of Mankind for over a thousand standard years.\n\nThe Blood Angels are the noble descendants of that most puissant and angelic of the primarchs -- Sanguinius. They are perhaps one of the most celebrated Chapters in the entire Imperium, their countless heroic deeds and victories known to untold billions of the Emperor\'s subjects across the length and breadth of the galaxy.\n\nThe beauteous, angelic visages of the Chapter\'s heroes adorn Gothic facades and stained glass windows in a million holy basilicas, and their portraits gaze serenely from endlessly copied and much cherished illuminated tomes.</string>
    <string name="blood_angels_quote">They are the sons of the Angel, the blooded host, the defenders of Humanity. They are strength. They are nobility. They are the Blood Angels, and I say to you there are no more loyal or determined servants of the Emperor alive today.</string>
    <string name="blood_angels_quote_source">High Lord Baldus Bael</string>

    <string name="chaos_daemons_name">Chaos Daemons</string>
    <string name="chaos_daemons_desc">Chaos Daemons, also known as \"Neverborn\" amongst the forces of Chaos, are intelligent and usually malevolent entities of the Warp comprised of purely psychic energy. Daemons are both sentient and self-aware embodiments of Chaos and collectively the greatest servants of the Chaos Gods and of Chaos itself as a universal force.\n\nDaemons are created at the whim of one of the four major Chaos Gods from a fraction of the god\'s own power within the Immaterium and act as an extension of its will. A Daemon\'s appearance and intrinsic character reflect the god\'s own nature. These Daemons may be reabsorbed into the god\'s psychic signature in the Warp at their whim.\n\nThe Chaos Gods are not alone in Warpspace. They have created servants from their own essences -- the creatures that mortals have named \"Daemons\" based on their ancient legends and religious mythologies -- who are not so closely bound to the Warp. Daemons are entities of a somewhat different nature to their masters, and are the most numerous of the creatures to be found in the Empyrean.\n\nA Daemon is \"born\" when a Chaos God expends a portion of its own power to create a separate being. This psychic power binds a collection of senses, thoughts and purposes together, creating a separate but closely related personality and consciousness that can move within the Warp.</string>
    <string name="chaos_daemons_quote">With the thirty-seven keys of Tzeentch, we open the way for our brothers. With the thousand whispers of Slaanesh, we call to them. With the twelve plagues of Nurgle, we fell their enemies. And with the mighty axe of Khorne, we cut open the world for them.</string>
    <string name="chaos_daemons_quote_source">Amphion and Zethus, Word Bearers Sorcerers</string>

    <string name="chaos_knights_name">Chaos Knights</string>
    <string name="chaos_knights_desc">The Chaos Knights, also known as Renegade Knights, Daemon Knights, and the Questor Traitoris in High Gothic, are Imperial Knight combat walkers, their Fallen Noble pilots and Knight houses corrupted to the service of Chaos.\n\nHumanoid war engines that tower over their foes, each Chaos Knight carries an army\'s worth of firepower upon its weaponised limbs and hulking carapace.\n\nAt close quarters, their roaring Reaper Chainswords and crushing Thunderstrike Gauntlets destroy what their trampling feet cannot, scattering terrified survivors before their unstoppable advance. The ground shudders beneath the godlike tread of the Renegade Knights.\n\nEven one such looming war engine possesses the firepower to annihilate entire regiments of enemy warriors, pick apart armoured columns, and swat squadrons of aircraft from the skies. Chaos Lords and rebellious demagogues will go to great lengths to secure the services of such a lone warrior, sacrificing whatever they must to ensure that this god of destruction fights at their side.\n\nDeployed in great number, the Questor Traitoris are more fearsome still, and have been known to bring entire worlds to heel, scourging them by blade and flame in the name of the Dark Gods.</string>
    <string name="chaos_knights_quote">Open your heart to hatred. Open your mind to fury. Open your soul to the Dark Ones. Let not your forebears stand between you and the power that is offered. The sun has set on the Age of Chivalry, and the night that is to come belongs to those with the strength to assert their rule.</string>
    <string name="chaos_knights_quote_source">Canticle of the Warped Becoming, from the Liber Idolator</string>

    <string name="chaos_space_marines_name">Chaos Space Marines</string>
    <string name="chaos_space_marines_desc">Chaos Space Marines, also sometimes called Traitor Marines, Renegade Marines, or Heretic Astartes, are former Space Marines of the Imperium of Man who have chosen to abandon the service of the Emperor of Mankind and dedicate themselves to Chaos to achieve their own ends.\n\nSuch corrupt Astartes usually belong to one of the nine original Traitor Legions that betrayed the Emperor during the ancient civil war called the Horus Heresy more than 10,000 standard years ago, while others come from Space Marine Chapters created long after the Heresy ended that have turned Renegade. Chaos can corrupt Astartes of any time and place just as its siren call leads many lesser men and women to their damnation.\n\nThe flesh and power armour of Chaos Space Marines often warps and twists into new, darker and inhuman forms under the influence of the Warp energies they are exposed to as their shapes morph to embody the corrupted Astartes\' new allegiance.\n\nChaos Space Marines fight for everything they were once forbidden to indulge in as the ascetic servants of the Emperor and the selfless guardians of Mankind. Pleasure, wealth, mayhem, but above all else, the power to rule their fellow Humans in the name of the Chaos Gods is the driving ambition and goal of every Chaos Space Marine.</string>
    <string name="chaos_space_marines_quote">Butcher your enemy\'s warriors without mercy. Crush his armies and leave none alive. But do not stop there. Burn his cities. Bomb his worlds from orbit. Slaughter everything and everyone until he kneels in the ashes of those he sought to protect. Only then will he understand the true fury of the Dark Gods.</string>
    <string name="chaos_space_marines_quote_source">Haakor of the Black Legion</string>

    <string name="dark_angels_name">Dark Angels</string>
    <string name="dark_angels_desc">The Dark Angels are considered amongst the most powerful and secretive of the Loyalist Space Marine Chapters. They were the Ist Legion of the original 20 Space Marine Legions to be created during the First Founding of the 30th Millennium.\n\nThough they claim complete allegiance and service to the Emperor of Mankind, their actions and secret goals at times seem at odds with that professed loyalty, as the Dark Angels strive above all other things to atone for an ancient crime of betrayal committed over 10,000 standard years ago against the trust of the Emperor during the time of the Horus Heresy.\n\nThe Dark Angels stand first amongst the Space Marine Chapters, as they have done since their very inception as the Ist Legion. They are a proud Chapter, with traditions and rituals that date back to the earliest days of the Imperium of Man.\n\nThe Dark Angels\' terrible secret is this: during the Horus Heresy, some of their brethren were turned to the side of Chaos. The Renegades were defeated in a battle that destroyed the Dark Angels\' Legion homeworld, Caliban, but many of the Traitor Dark Angels survived to be cast through space and time by the direct intervention of the Chaos Gods.</string>
    <string name="dark_angels_quote">Empires, monuments and legends are built by thbose who are merely victorious. We were born to kill, not to build. We are not idle long enough to leave monuments and we leave no work of the enermy intact to spawn legends. We are the Ist Legion, and he that follows in our wake is death.</string>
    <string name="dark_angels_quote_source">Hector Thrane, Keeper of the Black Gate and First Master of the Ist Legion</string>

    <string name="death_guard_name">Death Guard</string>
    <string name="death_guard_desc">The Death Guard are one of the Traitor Legions of Chaos Space Marines. They worship and devote themselves exclusively to the Chaos God Nurgle and as a result of his mutational \"gifts\" they have become Plague Marines; Heretic Astartes who are eternally rotting away within their power armour and infected with every known form of disease and decay but who are immune to all pain or minor injury.\n\nWhen the XIVth Legion was first raised on Terra by the Emperor during the First Founding, its Astartes were known as the Dusk Raiders. After the XIVth Legion was reunited with its Primarch Mortarion on the world of Barbarus, he renamed the Legion the Death Guard.\n\nThe Death Guard are a Traitor Legion entirely steeped in the power of Nurgle, the Chaos God of death, disease and despair, their very essence the epitome of all that vile Chaos God stands for. Their bodies are hives of filth and decay, their ﬂesh eternally rotting away even as it is renewed by the ceaseless process of death and rebirth.\n\nTo this day, Mortarion\'s Death Guard launch their assaults through the Cadian Gate and into the galaxy beyond, sometimes in large bodies and at others lending strength to allied Chaos forces. Wherever they travel they spread the joyful, exuberant poxes of Nurgle, gifting those who would know eternal life with the choicest of the Plague God\'s blessings.</string>
    <string name="death_guard_quote">In the embrace of great Nurgle, I am no longer afraid, for with His pestilential favour I have become that which I once feared: Death.</string>
    <string name="death_guard_quote_source">Kulvain Hestarius of the Death Guard</string>

    <string name="deathwatch_name">Deathwatch</string>
    <string name="deathwatch_desc">The Deathwatch, known also as the \"Long Vigil,\" and the \"Long Watch,\" is a unique Chapter of the Adeptus Astartes comprised solely of Veteran Space Marines that serves the Ordo Xenos of the Imperial Inquisition as its Chamber Militant. They are the warriors of last resort when the Inquisition needs access to firepower greater than that which the Astra Militarum or a team of its own Acolytes or Throne Agents can provide.\n\nAcross the galaxy there are innumerable hostile alien civilisations that threaten Humanity, from the green-skinned Orks, to the monstrous Tyranids, sadistic Drukhari, spectral C\'tan, and undying Necrons.\n\nIt is the sacred task of the Deathwatch to stand sentry against all of these terrible xenos races and many more besides. They are ready to act when such ancient evils rise to threaten Mankind once more. The Space Marines of the Deathwatch form the first, and often only, line of defence against these inhuman horrors.\n\nUnlike other Space Marines, the ones serving in the Deathwatch are not truly a separate Chapter of the Adeptus Astartes; rather, they are a collection of Veteran Space Marines drawn from all of the different extant Chapters who serve together in the Inquisition\'s service for a discrete period of time.\n\nTo be chosen by one\'s Chapter to serve in the Long Vigil of the Deathwatch is a great honour for any Space Marine. Only the most elite and experienced members of a Chapter are ever chosen for this extremely hazardous tour of duty, the specifics of which must be kept secret by Inquisitorial order and sacred oath even from a Deathwatch Astartes\' home Chapter.</string>
    <string name="deathwatch_quote">Amongst a hundred men, there may be none fit for the Adeptus Astartes. Amongst a hundred Space Marines, there may be one fit for the Deathwatch.</string>
    <string name="deathwatch_quote_source">Watch Captain Brand</string>

    <string name="drukhari_name">Drukhari</string>
    <string name="drukhari_desc">The Drukhari, or \"Dark Ones\" in the Aeldari Lexicon, also known to outsiders as the Dark Eldar, are a forsaken and corrupt Aeldari kindred, the sadistic, malicious counterparts of the Asuryani. Like their cousins of the craftworlds, the Drukhari are an ancient and highly advanced alien race of fey humanoids.\n\nThe Drukhari\'s armies, like their Craftworld Aeldari counterparts, usually have the advantages of mobility and advanced technology, though they are often lacking in resilience and numbers.\n\nThe Drukhari revel in piracy, enslavement and torture, and are sadistic in the extreme. Drukhari armies make use of various anti-gravity skimmers such as Raiders and Ravagers to launch high speed attacks. They strike with little or no warning, using an interdimensional labyrinth known as the Webway to traverse the galaxy safely and far more quickly than most advanced starfaring species are able to with their Warp jumps.\n\nThe Drukhari are unique amongst the intelligent species of the Milky Way Galaxy because they do not live on a settled world or worlds, but rather the bulk of their population is concentrated in one foul city-state -- the Dark City of Commorragh -- that lies within the \"ordered\" Immaterium of the Aeldari Webway.\n\nThe Drukhari are mainly pirates and slavers who prey on targets across the galaxy to feed their unholy appetites for other sentient beings\' souls, a terrible desire called \"the Thirst,\" though they are sometimes used as mercenaries by other starfaring species.</string>
    <string name="drukhari_quote">We are the lords of despair, masters of terror. Dread and agony are our meat and wine, and they are plentiful indeed!</string>
    <string name="drukhari_quote_source">Asdrubael Vect</string>

    <string name="genestealer_cults_name">Genestealer Cults</string>
    <string name="genestealer_cults_desc">A Genestealer Cult is a xenos-worshipping secret society made up of and controlled by Tyranid Genestealers that thrives in the dark corners of the Imperial underworld across the galaxy. Secretive, stealthy, and utterly malignant, Genestealer Cults are the cancers growing unseen in the hidden spaces of Mankind\'s realm.\n\nTheir purpose is to rise up and take control of Imperial worlds in the name of a xenos god that is actually a Tyranid Hive Fleet. Once the world is under their control, the cultists\' psychic emanations are picked up by the closest Hive Fleet\'s extension of the Hive Mind which is then drawn to consume the world, cultists and all.\n\nSome cultists are truly monstrous, skulking along dank tunnels with robes or hessian sacks covering their hybrid xenos anatomies. Others are merely pallid and bald, able to pass for loyal Imperial citizens whilst their wyrm-form tattoos remain hidden.\n\nOnce their brotherhood becomes strong enough, and all is in place for their great uprising, the Genestealer Cult will make its play. The militant throng boils by the thousand from sewers, tunnels and basements, seeping from the spires high above like insects pouring from a hidden nest. On this darkly glorious day of war, the cult\'s warriors are already ten steps ahead of the enemy.</string>
    <string name="genestealer_cults_quote">We are biological perfection. We blend the ingenuity and cunning of Mankind with the blessings of the Star Children. We are stronger, faster, more intelligent than any who challenge us. We will take that which is ours from the upworlders, and remake it in the image of our true masters. It is our destiny.</string>
    <string name="genestealer_cults_quote_source">Monthros Amaparha, Speaker of Galactic Truths</string>

    <string name="grey_knights_name">Grey Knights</string>
    <string name="grey_knights_desc">The Grey Knights are a secret and mysterious Chapter of Space Marines specifically tasked with combating the dangerous daemonic entities of the Warp and all those who wield the corrupt power of the Chaos Gods. They were created by the Emperor with the aid of Malcador the Sigillite at the time of the Horus Heresy to serve as Humanity\'s greatest weapon against the threat posed by the existence of Chaos.\n\nThey have the honour of being implanted with gene-seed engineered directly from the genome of the Emperor Himself.\n\nThe Grey Knights act as the military arm or \"Chamber Militant\" of the Ordo Malleus, the Daemonhunters who form the oldest branch of the virtually omnipotent Inquisition. The Grey Knights\' fortress-monastery, the Citadel of Titan, is based on Titan, the largest of the moons of the gas giant Saturn in the Sol System. It is kept as a private preserve of the Inquisition.\n\nThe existence of the Chapter is virtually unknown outside of the Inquisition and the highest echelons of the Imperial adepta, and is a well-guarded secret enforced by mind-wipes and even assassination of Imperial citizens if necessary.\n\nUnlike other Astartes, every Grey Knight is a potent psyker. Yet, in the 10,000 standard years of Imperial history, no Grey Knight has ever been corrupted by the Ruinous Powers of Chaos.</string>
    <string name="grey_knights_quote">We are the warriors of the Grey Knights, armoured in faith, shielded by devotion and armed with purity of purpose. But greater even than these, we carry the light of the divine Emperor of Man into the dark places to purge the daemonic wherever it may be found.</string>
    <string name="grey_knights_quote_source">Brother-Captain Arvann Stern</string>

    <string name="imperial_agents_name">Imperial Agents</string>
    <string name="imperial_agents_desc">A dominion as vast as the Imperium requires all kinds of agencies to keep it running, from the fastidious scribes and accountants of the Adeptus Administratum to the void-faring Imperial Navy. Most of these organisations maintain their own cadres of professional troops for when things get dicey on their own patch. These are the Imperial Agents, a disparate collection of house troops, irregulars, and specialist operatives sometimes seconded to other parts of the Imperial war machine when their expertise may prove useful.\n\nThe Inquisition are perhaps the best known of these disparate agencies, a group with absolute unquestionable authority to prosecute their judgement on the citizens of the Imperium.\n\nImperial Agents are ruthless, influential, and single-minded individuals, from Inquisitors to Rogue Traders, who command bands of grim specialists and lethal operatives in the service of the Emperor.</string>
    <string name="imperial_agents_quote">We are at War with forces too terrible to comprehend. We cannot afford mercy for any of its victims too weak to take the correct course. Mercy destroys us; it weakens us and saps our resolve. Put aside all such thoughts. They are not worthy of Inquisitors in the service of Our Emperor. Praise His name for in our resolve we only reflect his purpose of will.</string>
    <string name="imperial_agents_quote_source">The Book of Exorcisms, the Verses of Inquisitor Enoch</string>

    <string name="imperial_knights_name">Imperial Knights</string>
    <string name="imperial_knights_desc">The Imperial Knights, or Questor Imperialis in High Gothic, are piloted robotic combat walkers of small to medium size in the service of the Imperium and sometimes the Adeptus Mechanicus.\n\nEach Knight is piloted by a single Human warrior drawn from an ancient feudal aristocratic culture that stretches across the galaxy.\n\nHowever, a Knight is smaller and less capable in combat than even the smallest class of true Titan utilised by the Collegia Titanica, the Warhound-class Scout Titan. Knights normally deploy in squadrons comprised of several of these war machines.\n\nThese ancient battlesuits stand thirty to forty Terran feet (9 to 12 metres) tall, are protected by nearly impenetrable Ion Shields and armed with a devastating array of heavy weapons.\n\nImperial Knights are colossal war machines that tower over the battlefield. They are propelled into battle by powerful servos and have the power to kick over tanks and crush soldiers into red paste.\n\nVulnerable limbs and joints are protected by sweeping armour plates of adamantium and supported by an incorporated Ion Shield which responds to the thought-commands of its Noble pilot. The presence of just one of these towering engines of destruction is enough to change the course of a battle, and only the Titans of the Adeptus Mechanicus are more feared by the enemies of Mankind.</string>
    <string name="imperial_knights_quote">Let the power of your Knight flow through your veins. Let the ghosts of your throne whisper wisdom into your mind. Let steel be your sinews and fire be your fists. Become your Knight, as it becomes you, and through symbiosis ascend. So shall you become. So shall you protect your people and slaughter your foes.</string>
    <string name="imperial_knights_quote_source">Sixth Canticle of the Ritual of Becoming</string>

    <string name="leagues_of_votann_name">Leagues of Votann</string>
    <string name="leagues_of_votann_desc">The Leagues of Votann are the collective confederations of the species of squat but powerfully-built Abhuman clones who refer to themselves as the \"Kin.\" They are sometimes pejoratively called \"Squats\" by the Humans of the Imperium. The Kin are an advanced, starfaring race who possess highly advanced technology and live amid the extreme environments that mark the resource-rich worlds of the galactic core. The Kin share their lives with self-aware, robotic constructs called Ironkin, which they treat as full societal equals in every way.\n\nThe Kin have sometimes been misidentified by Humans and xenos species alike as different Abhuman or alien species than their true identity. For instance, the Kin have been mistakenly known to both the T\'au and Humans as the \"Demiurg,\" to the Aeldari as the \"Heliosi Ancients,\" and to various other peoples as the \"Gnostari,\" the \"Grome\" or the \"Kreg,\" among others.\n\nThe Kin vary in their classification by the Imperium between a sanctioned Abhuman sub-species of Humanity or a xenos species. However, the Kin\'s earliest surviving records do establish an ancient link between their Ancestors who settled the galactic core and the sublight, generational Long March mining fleets sent out by pre-Imperial Old Earth, thus making the Abhuman designation the correct one. For their part, the Kin care little what others think of them.\n\nEach of the Leagues of Votann are divided up into groupings similar to clans or nation-states known as \"Kindreds,\" and are ultimately led by a self-aware machine intelligence called a Votann or \"Ancestor Core.\" The Votann are treated as objects of near-worship by the Kin, and when they die, each Kin and Ironkin has their cerebral data uploaded into their Kindred\'s Votann, a semi-mystical practice referred to as \"returning to the Ancestors.\"</string>
    <string name="leagues_of_votann_quote">There\'s three things that matter in this galaxy: family; duty; Hearth. Every Kin lives by this code and anyone who gets in the way, well, they can die by it just as easily.</string>
    <string name="leagues_of_votann_quote_source">Kâhl Annôkh of the Starbreaker Kindred</string>

    <string name="necrons_name">Necrons</string>
    <string name="necrons_desc">The Necrons are a mysterious xenos species of humanoid, robotic skeletal warriors that have lain dormant in their stasis-tombs for more than 60 million Terran years, though they have begun to awaken at last. They are the soulless creations, former servants and now the captors of the ancient C\'tan, the terrible Star Gods of Aeldari myth.\n\nThe Necrons are ancient beyond reckoning, predating even the birth of the Aeldari. At long last, however, they are beginning to awaken from their Tomb Worlds, for the galaxy is ripe for conquest and the restoration of the Necron Empire since the disappearance of the Old Ones more than 60 million standard years ago.\n\nThe Necrons are a completely robotic humanoid species whose technological prowess is probably unmatched by any of the other intelligent species of the galaxy. Yet out of a desire for vengeance against the more fortunate, long-lived, ancient xenos people called the Old Ones, and the trickery of the godlike intelligences known as the C\'tan, the Necrons shed their original organic forms and lost all forms of compassion and empathy.\n\nThey have become instead ruthless, undying killing machines who are determined to exert their mastery over the galaxy once more. Across the galaxy, this ancient and terrible species is stirring back to life. Entombed in stasis-crypts for millions of Terran years, they have slumbered through the aeons, waiting for the galaxy to heal from the wounds of a long and bloody war.</string>
    <string name="necrons_quote">What care I that my legions are faceless? Identity matters only to those who have the ability to think: my Immortals and Lychguard, perhaps; my Lords and Crypteks, certainly. For the remainder of my vassals? Well, suffice to say that the concept of glory is wasted on the inglorious.</string>
    <string name="necrons_quote_source">Imotekh the Stormlord, Phaeron of the Sautekh Dynasty, Regent of Mandragora</string>

    <string name="orks_name">Orks</string>
    <string name="orks_desc">The Orks, also called Greenskins, are a savage, warlike, green-skinned species of bestial, asexual humanoids who are spread all across the galaxy. They are unique in that they possess the physiological features of both animals and fungi. They share many physical and cultural features with the dark fantasy Warhammer universe\'s Orcs (and were initially called \"Space Orcs\" to distinguish them).\n\nOrks are seen by their enemies (pretty much everyone else in the universe) as primitive, barbaric, hyper-violent, and crude, but they are the most successful and widepsread intelligent species in the whole galaxy, outnumbering possibly every other intelligent starfaring species, even Humanity (with the very plausible exception of the Tyranids).\n\nGreenskins are one of the most dangerous alien races to plague the galaxy. Numerous beyond belief and driven always to fight and conquer, the Orks threaten every single intelligent species of the galaxy.\n\nOrks are possibly the most warlike aliens in the 41st Millennium, and their number is beyond counting. Amid constant, seething tides of battle and bloodshed, burgeoning Ork stellar empires rise and fall.\n\nMercifully most are short-lived, soon destroying themselves in a maelstrom of violence and internecine conflict, but should the Orks ever truly unify, they would crush all opposition.\n\nOrks generate a potent psychic gestalt field that allows them to accomplish many feats of technological engineering that might otherwise seem impossible. At the same time, the power of this psychic field is directly proportional to the number of Greenskins present in a given location.\n\nThe more Orks that gather, the more Orks are drawn to them, at the same time that the power and intelligence of the Greenskins begins to grow with their numbers.</string>
    <string name="orks_quote">Of all the races I have battled throughout the galaxy, the Ork is the hardest to comprehend. They wage war with machines that should not work, care little for strategic gains, and are just as likely to slaughter each other as the enemy. How does one battle an enemy that defies all logic?</string>
    <string name="orks_quote_source">Rogue Trader Varnael Larik</string>

    <string name="space_marines_name">Space Marines</string>
    <string name="space_marines_desc">The Space Marines or Adeptus Astartes are foremost amongst the defenders of Humanity, the greatest of the Emperor of Mankind\'s warriors. They are barely Human at all, but superhuman; having been made superior in all respects to a normal man by a harsh regime of genetic modification, psycho-conditioning and rigorous training.\n\nSpace Marines are untouched by plague or any natural disease and can suffer wounds that would kill a lesser being several times over, and live to fight again. Clad in ancient power armour and wielding the most potent weapons known to man, the Space Marines are terrifying foes and their devotion to the Emperor and the Imperium of Man is unyielding. They are the God-Emperor\'s Angels of Death, and they know no fear.\n\nThe Astartes are physically stronger, far more resilient and often mentally far removed from the lot of most normal Human beings. In the presence of the Astartes, most people feel a combination of awe and fear, and many cultures on the more primitive worlds simply worship them outright as demigods or angels of the God-Emperor made flesh.\n\nThey should feel so, for many Space Marines feel little compassion for those they have sometimes termed \"mortals\" in comparison to themselves, seeing the very people they were created to protect as little more than obstacles to a more efficient eradication of the Imperium\'s enemies.</string>
    <string name="space_marines_quote">They shall be my finest warriors, these men who give of themselves to me. Like clay I shall mould them and in the furnace of war I shall forge them. They shall be of iron will and steely sinew. In great armour I shall clad them and with the mightiest weapons shall they be armed. They will be untouched by plague or disease; no sickness shall blight them. They shall have such tactics, strategies and machines that no foe will best them in battle. They are my bulwark against the Terror. They are the Defenders of Humanity. They are my Space Marines...and they shall know no fear.</string>
    <string name="space_marines_quote_source">The Emperor of Mankind</string>

    <string name="space_wolves_name">Space Wolves</string>
    <string name="space_wolves_desc">The Space Wolves, known in their own dialect of Juvjk as the Vlka Fenryka or \"Wolves of Fenris,\" are one of the original 20 First Founding Space Marine Chapters, and were once led by their famed primarch, Leman Russ. Originally the VIth Legion of Astartes raised by the Emperor at the dawn of the Great Crusade, the Space Wolves are renowned for their anti-authoritarian ways and their embrace of their homeworld Fenris\' savage barbarian culture as well as their extreme deviation from the Codex Astartes in the Chapter\'s organisation.\n\nAfter the Horus Heresy and the resultant Second Founding reforms of the Adeptus Astartes, the Space Wolves Legion was divided into two Chapters: the new Space Wolves Chapter, which was not compliant with the dictates of the Codex Astartes and retained the name of its parent Space Marine Legion, and the second Chapter which took the name of the Wolf Brothers. The Wolf Brothers suffered from rampant mutation of their gene-seed not long after their Founding and were later disbanded.\n\nOnly recently in the Era Indomitus have new successors of the Space Wolves been raised; though many Space Wolves still have doubts about whether the Primaris Marines raised from the genetic material of Leman Russ are true sons of the primarch, the Great Wolf Logan Grimnar has accepted them into the fold as warriors worthy of the Wolf King\'s heritage.\n\nSince the Imperium came into being, the Space Wolves have fought tooth and nail for the cause of the Emperor. Amongst the most famous of the Chapters of the Adeptus Astartes in the wider Imperium, their sagas are told from one end of the galaxy to the other. As headstrong as they are fierce, the Space Wolves excel at close-quarters fighting, their warriors vying keenly for glory on the field of battle. The Space Wolves live to fight, and death holds even less fear for them than their counterparts in other Chapters.</string>
    <string name="space_wolves_quote">The Sons of Fenris they are, hardened in the forge of their harsh world, eager for battle and honour. They are the grey warriors, ashen like the wolf, whose greatest joy is to hear the clamour of steel amidst the din of war.</string>
    <string name="space_wolves_quote_source">The Space Wolves Catechism</string>

    <string name="thousand_sons_name">Thousand Sons</string>
    <string name="thousand_sons_desc">The Thousand Sons are one of the Traitor Legions of Chaos Space Marines who are sworn solely to the service of Tzeentch, the Chaos God of change, intrigue and sorcery, though they were once the Imperium of Man\'s XVth Legion of Space Marines. The main feature that distinguishes the Thousand Sons from the other Traitor Legions is the sheer number of psyker mutations that have always existed amongst the Space Marines in this Legion.\n\nEvery current member of the Legion possesses psychic abilities and they prefer to use Chaos Sorcerers and guile in combat, relying on their psychic powers and sorcerous knowledge to earn them victory.\n\nAs a result of an ancient spell known as the Rubric of Ahriman that was cast soon after the Thousand Sons fell from their homeworld of Prospero during the early days of the Horus Heresy, every Thousand Sons Astartes that lacked psychic powers had his soul fused directly into his power armour. The Thousand Sons have become living embodiments of sorcery animated by the power of Chaos and the will of the Lord of Change.\n\nThe Thousand Sons are the scions of the Primarch Magnus the Red, the copper-skinned cyclops whose thirst for knowledge in all its forms led ultimately to damnation and an eternity of servitude to Tzeentch, the Chaos God known as the Changer of the Ways. When the primarchs were scattered throughout the galaxy, Magnus found himself coming to rest upon the distant, isolated colony world of Prospero.</string>
    <string name="thousand_sons_quote">The minds of gods are not for mortals to know, or to judge. Accept that Tzeentch has a place for all of us in his grand scheme, and be happy in the part you have to play.</string>
    <string name="thousand_sons_quote_source">Magnus the Red</string>

    <string name="tyranids_name">Tyranids</string>
    <string name="tyranids_desc">The Tyranids are an extragalactic composite species of hideous, insectoid xenos. They actually comprise an entire space-faring ecosystem comprised of innumerable different bioforms which are all variations on the same genetic theme.\n\nThe Tyranids are unlike any other intelligent species encountered by Humanity. They are the ultimate predators; to them, all living things, from the lowliest insect to the most advanced starfaring civilisation, are mere prey. Only now are the inhabitants of the galaxy realising the scale of the threat; unless the Tyranids can be stopped, it will mean nothing less than the extinction of all life.\n\nThe Tyranid species is ultimately dedicated solely to its own survival, propagation and evolutionary advancement. The Tyranids collectively form a monstrous superorganism that travels across the universe in their great hive fleets of biomechanical Hive Ships, systematically consuming all other biomatter to enable their own rapid evolution and reproduction.\n\nThe Tyranids are likened to a galactic swarm consuming everything in its path, feeding on entire worlds and leaving only dead husks in their wake. Their threat is such that an unprotected planet can be infested and stripped clean of all its organic material in a matter of solar weeks without even slowing down the advance of the hive fleet.\n\nAll Tyranid organisms are \"synaptic\" (psychically-reactive), and each Tyranid creature within a hive fleet shares and contributes to a communal Hive Mind, which allows the trillions of beings comprising the Tyranid hive fleets to communicate and organise instantaneously on a staggering scale.</string>
    <string name="tyranids_quote">There is a cancer eating at the Imperium. With each decade it advances deeper, leaving drained, dead worlds in its wake. This horror, this abomination, has thought and purpose which functions on an unimaginable, galactic scale and all we can do is try to stop the swarms of bio-engineered monsters it unleashes upon us by instinct. We have given the horror a name to salve our fears; we call it the Tyranid race, but if it is aware of us at all it must know us only as Prey.</string>
    <string name="tyranids_quote_source">Inquisitor Bronislaw Czevak</string>

    <string name="tau_name">T\'au Empire</string>
    <string name="tau_desc">The T\'au Empire is a rapidly expanding, multispecies xenos stellar empire situated within the Imperium of Man\'s Ultima Segmentum, near the Eastern Fringes of the Milky Way Galaxy. It lies within the reach of the Astronomican.\n\nThe T\'au Empire was founded by the T\'au caste called the Ethereals, who lead the T\'au Empire in the name of and in accordance with the utilitarian philosophy they have named the \"Greater Good\" (Tau\'va in the T\'au Lexicon). A large and growing number of other intelligent, alien races have allied themselves with the T\'au within the empire.\n\nThe empire has suffered many raids from the Orks, and also seems to lie in the path of several Tyranid splinter fleets of Hive Fleet Kraken.\n\nThe T\'au (Imperial binomial classification: Tau tau), also spelled \"Tau\" in older Imperial records, are a young, humanoid and technologically-advanced intelligent species native to the Eastern Fringes of the Milky Way Galaxy. They are fighting to expand their small, but rapidly growing, interstellar empire and extend a philosophical concept they call the \"Greater Good\" to all the intelligent species of the galaxy.\n\nThe T\'au claim to be a peaceful species when possible, asking if others will join their cause voluntarily instead of fighting against them. However, if their peaceful overtures are refused, the T\'au may well decide to conquer a planet and add it to their growing stellar empire for the Greater Good, searing the flesh from the bones of anyone who stands against their benign intentions.</string>
    <string name="tau_quote">We are five castes, one people. We stand united, dedicated wholly to the Greater Good. As we progress, we will encounter further barriers. We will overcome them. Our future is now, believe in our destiny.</string>
    <string name="tau_quote_source">Ethereal Supreme Aun\'Va</string>

    <string name="world_eaters_name">World Eaters</string>
    <string name="world_eaters_desc">The World Eaters are one of the Traitor Legions of Chaos Space Marines who now inhabit the Warp rift known as the Eye of Terror in the Imperium of Man\'s Segmentum Obscurus.\n\nThe World Eaters, originally known as the War Hounds, were also once the XIIth Legion of the twenty First Founding Space Marine Legions, and one of the first to betray the Emperor of Mankind for the service of Chaos and the Warmaster Horus.\n\nThis Legion was a collection of nearly inhuman monsters long before Horus became corrupted and monsters they would remain, only with what little remained of their restraint and their Humanity stripped away after their fall to Chaos.\n\nThe World Eaters are now the dedicated servants of the Blood God Khorne, the Chaos God of war and murder, and live for nothing more than to spill blood in his name. The World Eaters\' Primarch Angron was one of the first of the Space Marine Primarchs to join with Horus when he turned against the Emperor and began the Horus Heresy.\n\nThe Legion is no longer united, having long ago surrendered to the pure bloodlust inspired by their patron Khorne. Instead they now operate as separate warbands of Chaos Space Marines who seek to spread death and terror in the name of the Blood God across the galaxy.\n\nThe World Eaters were known from their very inception as the most brutal and direct of assault troops. Their fearsome doctrine was very much the result of the early life of their Primarch.</string>
    <string name="world_eaters_quote">Make war upon the Imperium of Man? What is it you think the Legions have been doing for the last ten thousand years? War does not end with a single victory or a single planet. It is an eternal creature that outlives men and their tiny triumphs.</string>
    <string name="world_eaters_quote_source">Arzyn the Silencebringer</string>
</resources>